RG 079:023, Water Resources Commission
Connecticut State Library
Water Resources Commission records
1925-1981
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut Water Resources Commission
4.5 cubic feet
The State Water Commission was created in 1925 to reduce, control or eliminate water pollution. It merged into the Water Resources Commission in 1957 that was formed to study the water resources of the State.
RG079_023
Multiple
Historical Note
The State Water Commission was established in 1925 by Public Acts chpt. 143. Its function was to determine through hearing if "any person, fir, or corporation is polluting the waters of the state" and if finding that to be the case then it "may make an order directing such person, firm or corporation to use or to operate some practicable and reasonably available system or means which will reduce, control or eliminate such pollution having regard for the rights and interests of all persons concerned, provided the cost of installation, maintenance and operation thereof shall not be unreasonable or inequitable." On June 1, 1957, the State Water Commission merged with the State Flood Control and water Policy Commission and the State Board of Supervision of Dams to form the Water Resources Commission. The new Commission's purpose was to "study the water resources of the State and the present laws pertaining thereto. It shall further study the relative needs of the various groups represented on said commission with particular reference to the greatest good to the people." In 1971 the Water Resources Commission merged into the new Department of Environmental Protection.
See also the.
Scope and Content
Includes minutes of both the State Water Commission and the Water Resources Commission, 1925-1971; some biennial reports, 1938-1940; and some miscellaneous material that post-date the merge into the Department of Environmental Protection, most concerning the Insfrasturcture Task Force, 1983-1984.
Arrangement
Series 1. Minutes of meetings, 1925-1971, Accession: 1997-052
Series 2. Miscellaneous, circa 1937-1984, Accession: 1997-052
Series 3. Reports, 1938-1940, Accession: 2001-072
Related Material
RG 079:005, Department of Department of Environmental Protection: Aire, Waste and Water
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut. State Water Commission; Connecticut. Water Resources Commission
Subjects:
Connecticut. State Water Commission -- Records and correspondence; Connecticut. Water Resources Commission -- Records and correspondence; Water-supply -- Connecticut; Water pollution -- Connecticut; Water quality -- Connecticut; Water resources development -- Connecticut
Document Types:
Legislative acts; Minutes; Reports
Restrictions on Access
See the policy.
Container List
- Series 1. Minutes of meetings, 1925-1971; 1997-052
  - Minutes of meetings, 1925-1981
    - 1925 - 1957, 11 folders (Box 1)
    - 1958 - 1963, 6 folders (Box 2)
    - 1964 - 1966 September, 5 folders (Box 3)
    - 1966 October -1967 May, 1 volume (Box 9)
    - 1967 October - 1968 August, 12 folders (Box 4)
    - 1968 September - 1970 August, 16 folders (Box 5)
    - 1970 September -1971 September, 13 folders (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 6)
- Series 2. Miscellaneous, circa 1937-1984; 1997-052
  - Summary Record of Actions - Water Compliance, 1972-1973; 10 folders (Box 7)
  - Infrastructure Task Force, 1983-1984
    - Annual report, 1951 September (Box 8)
    - Report, "1968 Inventory Municipal Waste Facilities" (New England) (Box 8)
    - Middletown Sewage Treatment Plant - Operation records, 1937-1940 (Box 8)
    - State Laws, General Statutes - I (Box 8)
    - State Laws II (Box 8)
    - Connecticut Water Division Policy Act of 1982 (Box 8)
    - Act Establishing Commission and other Miscellaneous Acts (Box 8)
    - Federal Laws (Box 8)
    - Federal Laws, Regulations - Miscellaneous (Box 8)
- Series 3. Reports, 1938-1940; 2001-072
  Published copies of these reports can be found at
  - First biennial report of the State Water Commission 1925-1926, typescript (Box 1)
    Includes transmittal letter to Gov. John H. Trumbull, December 31, 1926; and Favorable report of the Joint Standing Committee on the Judiciary, January 1927.
  - Second biennial report of the State Water Commission for the years 1926-1928, typescript (Box 1)
    Includes transmittal letter to Gov. John H. Trumbull, January 8, 1929.
  - Third biennial report of the State Water Commission for the years 1928-30, 1930 (Box 1)
    State of Connecticut public document; no. 78
  - Seventh biennial report of the State Water Commission for the years 1936-1938, typescript (Box 1)
    Includes transmittal letter to Gov. Wilbur L. Cross, November 10, 1938.
  - Eighth biennial report of the State Water Commission for the years 1938-1940, typescript (Box 1)
    Includes transmittal letter to Gov. Raymond E. Bladwin, November 26, 1940.
- Series 4. Maps, 1939; 2009-039
  - Plan and profile, Flood of September 1938, Connecticut River, 1939 January; Prepared by: Connecticut Ground Water Survey; 2 sheets, 153 x 42 in.; Scale: 2 inches = 1 mile (Oversize Item 1)